[{"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c70", "question": "What was H.G. Wells' first novel?", "answer": "The Time Machine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b69b", "question": "What is the edible part of a sea urchin?", "answer": "The gonads", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9087f01dd7bf43be5e884", "question": "What is the most prominent crater on the Moon?", "answer": "Tycho", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a10", "question": "What year was the setting for the movie \"Animal House\"?", "answer": "1962", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ef", "question": "Which singer sang \"I Believe In Father Christmas''?", "answer": "Greg Lake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede3c76ce05a3942286dd6", "question": "What is Gary Oldman's character's codename in the 2011 spy drama \"Tinker, Tailor, Soldier, Spy\"?", "answer": "Beggarman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69c3420565ad31a57c769", "question": "What was the first city speed limit set by law for motor vehicles in America?", "answer": "12 MPH", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b494", "question": "Which country hosted the 1900 Olympic Games?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bcd", "question": "What is the supposed site of the Isle of Avalon?", "answer": "Glastonbury", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe1ecbc145fb29466707388", "question": "Where did fondue originate?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938c", "question": "What is Doc allergic to in the movie \"Back To The Future\"?", "answer": "Synthetics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9baa1364247bf200fb89a", "question": "What is the fear of death known as?", "answer": "Necrophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4dd8306d333868d34d703", "question": "Eric the Red was a Viking from what period of time?", "answer": "900s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b94f", "question": "What sport did hall-of-famer Mickey Mantle play?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f8", "question": "What is the name of the Volkswagen in Disney\u2019s \"The Love Bug\"?", "answer": "Herbie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b517", "question": "What is the only alcoholic drink one can buy in the dry Moore county in Tennessee?", "answer": "Jack Daniel's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c05b", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Panama?", "answer": "Harpy eagle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133990e", "question": "Who was musical director for Johnny Carson's \"The Tonight Show\" from 1967\u00ad to 1992?", "answer": "Doc Severinsen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe52fb81bf59ab7d2e38117", "question": "Where is Bank of America headquartered?", "answer": "Charlotte, North Carolina", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b6", "question": "Whose still-life painting, \"Rideau Cruchon et Compotier\", sold for $60.5 million in 1999?", "answer": "Paul Cezanne's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5971de3089261e916c8e09a1", "question": "In the US, a pint of milk is equal to how many cups of milk?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3d1c44f0f6af5b066637", "question": "Who had a hit in 1996 with the song \"Wannabe\"?", "answer": "Spice Girls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c62b7fa0ae4aacefc17eedf", "question": "Who are the Pines twins in the TV show \"Gravity Falls\"?", "answer": "Dipper and Mabel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66c4ea5bfecdd737e0892", "question": "Cynophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Dogs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cf27877e98cb97778a4b", "question": "Where are the Porcupine Mountains located?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4cd", "question": "What was the first man-made object to leave the Solar System?", "answer": "Voyager 1", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c0", "question": "What are female elephants called?", "answer": "Cows", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e58bfe83fe1f2a824bc0", "question": "Broadway was established in what year in New York?", "answer": "1750", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e72cc9ed0874f1a5e2d1c24", "question": "What is Michael J. Fox\u2019s middle name?", "answer": "Andrew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a47d20565ad31a57c7bd", "question": "Who was the first U.S. President born west of the Mississippi River?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339330", "question": "What actor played the role of Captain John McIntyre on the TV show \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Wayne Rogers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4a", "question": "What is the name for Germany's high-speed highways?", "answer": "Autobahn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd5a", "question": "What tropical fruit is the main ingredient in Thai som tam salad?", "answer": "Papaya", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf4f", "question": "What fish is known as poor mans lobster?", "answer": "Monk Fish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918d", "question": "Which is the only one of the Seven Dwarfs without a beard?", "answer": "Dopey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c255", "question": "What does a barometer measure?", "answer": "Atmospheric Pressure", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008b35cf842fa4c4ba9696", "question": "What composer wrote the \"Pomp and Circumstance\" marches?", "answer": "Edward Elgar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb5", "question": "What are the \"spots\" in the British dessert Spotted Dick?", "answer": "Currants", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a609", "question": "In which European country is the resort town of Spa?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c25", "question": "Which movie was Charlie Chaplin's last?", "answer": "A Countess from Hong Kong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a4", "question": "What fruit is grown extensively on Cape Cod?", "answer": "Cranberries", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe76643eec85e375820b27d", "question": "In which mountain range is the highest continuous paved road in the U.S.?", "answer": "Rocky Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a044", "question": "What alien did Ben 10 first turn into in \"Ben 10: Alien Force\"?", "answer": "Swampfire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523f68736d4be723796b58", "question": "What year were the Canada's Juno Awards first awarded?", "answer": "1970", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "595244e2736d4be723796b6a", "question": "How many scents can the human nose detect?", "answer": "More than 1 Trillion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d8", "question": "Which cartoon character had the vital statistics of 19-19-19?", "answer": "Olive Oyl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b48ae49076251badbeaa4", "question": "What space shuttle did John Glenn travel in when he returned to space?", "answer": "Discovery -- Glenn flew on\u00a0Space Shuttle\u00a0Discovery's\u00a0STS-95\u00a0mission in 1998.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4e", "question": "Which two US states share a border with Rhode Island?", "answer": "Connecticut and Massachusetts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fb1bffff497e33de805791b", "question": "What can be found inside a baseball?", "answer": "Rubber or cork, and yarn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8efe901dd7bf43be5e7f6", "question": "What is the official name for a blob of toothpaste on a toothbrush?", "answer": "Nurdle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c878", "question": "What's the world's largest predatory fish?", "answer": "The great white shark", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0f", "question": "What character, created by Hugh Lofting, could talk to animals?", "answer": "Dr. Dolittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c383", "question": "The water moccasin snake is also known as what?", "answer": "Cottonmouth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdc0eb5469bb8041d07a063", "question": "What is the process of preparing eggs for Caesar salad dressing called?", "answer": "Coddling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe733e0eec85e375820b227", "question": "What agreement, signed on September 27, 1940, created the Axis Powers?", "answer": "Tripartite Pact", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cfb6bb53d1af658864f5", "question": "The song \"Jingle Bell Rock\" is performed during the opening credits of which \"Lethal Weapon\" film?", "answer": "The first one", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3be", "question": "Which of Monaco's four quarters is best known for casinos?", "answer": "Monte Carlo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339825", "question": "What quintet featured Danny, Donnie, Joe, Jonathan and Jordan?", "answer": "New Kids on the Block", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a06", "question": "What D.H. Lawrence novel was originally titled \"Tenderness\"?", "answer": "Lady Chatterley's Lover", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afbf", "question": "Who was the first British monarch to live in Buckingham Palace?", "answer": "Queen Victoria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be20", "question": "Which of Santa's reindeer is named for a female fox?", "answer": "Vixen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c771", "question": "The Plato Scale is used specifically in the making of what beverage?", "answer": "Beer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f4e8ff048f679a45aacd", "question": "Megalophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Large things or objects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecda56ec223966ae8f88e8", "question": "What was the first movie for which the cost of obtaining rights to the soundtrack outweighed all other production costs?", "answer": "Clerks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdffbb61cf6db9ac4808cf7", "question": "What's the oldest university in England?", "answer": "Oxford University", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a630", "question": "What river defines the southern border of Oklahoma?", "answer": "Red River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59c1ce367bd84c0ea43ad434", "question": "On what river is the capital city of Canada located?", "answer": "Ottawa River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c192", "question": "Which breed of dog gets its name from the Latin for earth?", "answer": "Terrier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ccf", "question": "In which Hitchcock movie is the protagonist confined to a wheelchair?", "answer": "Rear Window", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b3f44fda37788a9a1dc6", "question": "Where is the Salvador Dali museum located?", "answer": "St. Petersburg, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a94c", "question": "The Republic of Upper Volta was the official name of which African country before August 1984?", "answer": "Burkina Faso", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b49", "question": "Who played Al Borland on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Richard Karn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba10", "question": "What does \"GIDP\" stand for in baseball?", "answer": "Ground into double play", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c09", "question": "The book \"Unsafe at Any Speed\", criticized what company?", "answer": "General Motors", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a437", "question": "The geothermal spa \"Blue Lagoon\" is located in what country?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca6", "question": "What 1986 Europe hit was Gob's magic act theme song on TV's \"Arrested Development\"?", "answer": "The Final Countdown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7bd", "question": "What is measured in Newtons?", "answer": "Force", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa3", "question": "What nationality was the architect Le Corbusier?", "answer": "Swiss-French", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1eb", "question": "Who released the album titled \"The Spaghetti Incident\"?", "answer": "Guns N' Roses", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a0", "question": "In the movie \"Raisin Arizona\", what magazine does Hi hide when they bring the baby home?", "answer": "Playboy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d1", "question": "The TV show \"King of the Hill\" was based in what US state?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e9", "question": "What group's 1979 debut album was entitled \"Reproduction\"?", "answer": "Human League", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aafa", "question": "Which country borders Chad to the north?", "answer": "Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a5", "question": "In what century was the original Star Trek set?", "answer": "The 23rd century", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bce", "question": "In what year did ABBA become officially a group?", "answer": "1973", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b178", "question": "When did the Sydney Opera House officially open its doors to the public?", "answer": "20 October 1973", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58be2d228faf425cf37add7b", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Oregon?", "answer": "Salem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5dc", "question": "What can be transverse, seif or star?", "answer": "Sand dunes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a210", "question": "Jason Voorhees' mask was molded from which NHL team's goalie mask?", "answer": "Detroit Red Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a96", "question": "\"The Tortelli's\" was the first attempt at a spin-off from what TV show?", "answer": "Cheers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dfb", "question": "What \"Fantasy Island\" actor ended up committing suicide?", "answer": "Herve Villechaize", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b722", "question": "What was used as the first Christmas collection kettle by the Salvation Army?", "answer": "A large crabpot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae6", "question": "How many strikes in a row earns you a perfect game in regular 10\u00ad pin bowling?", "answer": "12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffcfd279dc5ec6cd98a8321", "question": "Who painted Nu couch\u00e9?", "answer": "Amedeo Modigliani", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6000ed369a72b906b34e3cea", "question": "Which scientist formulated the law of universal gravitation?", "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8f", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Robert Diggs?", "answer": "RZA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a3", "question": "What stars of the movie \"Eyes Wide Shut\" divorced shortly after the film was made?", "answer": "Tom Cruise and Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05b", "question": "What is the name of Amy Winehouse's first album?", "answer": "Frank", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aedb", "question": "In which present-day country is the site of the battle of Waterloo?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339444", "question": "Who played Edward in the movie \"Edward Scissorhands\"?", "answer": "Johnny Depp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba83", "question": "Where did Saints quarterback Drew Brees play college football?", "answer": "Purdue University", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f3", "question": "Which famous Jazz club is the subject of a 1984 Francis Ford Coppola film?", "answer": "The Cotton Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde1", "question": "What two consecutive signs of the Zodiac begin with the same letter?", "answer": "Scorpio and Sagittarius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd660d6a5bfecdd737e0838", "question": "Who was the most Googled person of 2018?", "answer": "Meghan Markle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cb5", "question": "How many lines are in a sonnet?", "answer": "14", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b06f", "question": "What famous ship was sunk on May 7, 1915?", "answer": "The Lusitania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60078124bd51d85e222ab648", "question": "Vincent van Gogh painted \"The Starry Night\" while what?", "answer": "He painted\u00a0it while undergoing treatment at the Saint-Paul-de-Mausole,\u00a0a psychiatric hospital\u00a0in Saint-R\u00e9my-de-Provence.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f47", "question": "What is the real first name of Tyler Perry's famous character, Madea?", "answer": "Mabe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e60", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Stewie Griffin?", "answer": "Seth MacFarlane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a792", "question": "Trinidad and Tobago is part of which continent?", "answer": "North America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbb", "question": "What Beatles movie features bad guys called Blue Meanies?", "answer": "Yellow Submarine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d2", "question": "Which country hosted the 1982 FIFA World Cup?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b97", "question": "Whose movie debut was opposite Humphrey Bogart in 1944's \"To Have and Have Not\"?", "answer": "Lauren Bacall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f15101dd7bf43be5e804", "question": "What is the name of the gigantic silver sphere at EPCOT?", "answer": "Spaceship Earth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b17445bbb2d29f81593b6fa", "question": "Who wrote and starred in the 1922 version of the film \"Robin Hood\"?", "answer": "Douglas Fairbanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa55a6ce05a3942286ebf", "question": "What was Arnold Schwarzenegger's character's name in the film \"Total Recall\"?", "answer": "Dennis Quaid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a112", "question": "\"Dance with a Stranger\" was the film of who's life story?", "answer": "Ruth Ellis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7fb", "question": "Which fish does a chef need a special license for to be able to prepare in Japan?", "answer": "Fugu, or blowfish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cd40b2e685cf15b733e9888", "question": "What South American country's name comes from the Latin word for silver?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a02", "question": "What Shakespeare play is set on January 5?", "answer": "Twelfth Night", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab18bdbaab681b0929218e", "question": "Who is the world\u2019s largest tire manufacturer?", "answer": "LEGO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe73884eec85e375820b262", "question": "What is the world\u2019s largest Hydroelectric Power Plant?", "answer": "Three Gorges Dam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7de", "question": "Lake Champlain lies on the border between Vermont and which other US state?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c988fbde8045e48466ee", "question": "Which farm animal can purr, similar to a cat, when they are happy?", "answer": "Turkeys make a variety of sounds, including a soft, rolling call when they are happy, which is called a purr.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c835", "question": "Which space shuttle is named for the ship on which Robert Scott first sailed to Antarctica?", "answer": "The Discovery", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f32", "question": "What is the infirmity of Jake Barnes, the protagonist of \"The Sun Also Rises\"?", "answer": "He's impotent from a war wound", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cdc02e347d002c297e4e4", "question": "What is the capital of Belgium?", "answer": "Brussels", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fbe", "question": "What instrument did bandleader Glenn Miller play?", "answer": "Trombone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338978", "question": "What rock band's album \"The Piper at the Gates of Dawn\" was named after a chapter title from \"The Wind in the Willows\"?", "answer": "Pink Floyd's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339669", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", which breed of dog is Santa's Little Helper?", "answer": "Greyhound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f60", "question": "What supermodel plays the bride in Guns N' Roses' \"November Rain\" video?", "answer": "Stephanie Seymour", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596dfcfa9616e6c6d4eba4f3", "question": "What year did the video game Grand Theft Auto V come out?", "answer": "2013", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51b0dff04d658268c930c", "question": "Who discovered Odysseus when he washed up on Phaeacia?", "answer": "Princess Nausicaa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e14", "question": "George Orwell's \"Animal Farm\" is a roman \u00e0 clef for what historical event?", "answer": "The Russian Revolution", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb59", "question": "What was the nickname of professional boxing champion Thomas Hearns?", "answer": "Hitman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c07d", "question": "What is hippophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Horses", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdb69ec223966ae8f88f5", "question": "The script for what movie was written during shooting breaks on the set of \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "E.T.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a44", "question": "What author created the characters Ponyboy and Sodapop?", "answer": "S.E. Hinton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd5fde347d002c297e4b9", "question": "Which major horserace is held in Australia on the first Tuesday in November?", "answer": "The Melbourne Cup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa6bf73838c5c8a417f32", "question": "When held to ultraviolet light, what animal\u2019s urine glows in the dark?", "answer": "Cat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc7", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by David Bowie?", "answer": "Rebel Rebel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a490", "question": "What is the capital of Pakistan?", "answer": "Islamabad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfab", "question": "What are Tracy Thorn and Ben Watt collectively known as?", "answer": "Everything But The Girl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1df", "question": "In the restaurant world, what does \"Blue-plate special\" refer to?", "answer": "Low-priced specials that change daily", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b12d", "question": "What pacific atoll was the site of nuclear tests between 1946 and 1958?", "answer": "The Bikini Atoll", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eae", "question": "Who won Pulitzers for his plays \"A Delicate Balance\", \"Seascape\", and \"Three Tall Women\"?", "answer": "Edward Albee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a125", "question": "What do \"Tom\", \"Dick\", and \"Harry\" refer to in the film \"The Great Escape\"?", "answer": "The escape tunnels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad40", "question": "What was the name of the plane that dropped the atomic bomb on Nagasaki?", "answer": "Bockscar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb54", "question": "On what mountain does Moses speak to God through the burning bush and received the Ten Commandments?", "answer": "Mt. Sinai", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e7", "question": "What is the longest one syllable word in the English language?", "answer": "Screeched", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c009", "question": "In pool, what color is the eight ball?", "answer": "Black", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede34d6ce05a3942286dd1", "question": "Who was originally cast as Holly Golightly in \"Breakfast at Tiffany\u2019s\"?", "answer": "Marilyn Monroe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133993d", "question": "Who played the role of Bud Bundy on the TV show \"Married with Children\"?", "answer": "David Faustino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0e306fcbed638185eaa1f", "question": "Where is the United Nations (UN) Headquarters located?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ca3e7144f0f6af5b06664c", "question": "What did David Stirling form in 1941?", "answer": "SAS (Special Air Service)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133989d", "question": "What TV sitcom followed the lives of June, Ward, Wally and Theodore?", "answer": "Leave It To Beaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cae1", "question": "Some animals spend the winter in a sleep-like state known as what?", "answer": "Hibernation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10e", "question": "During WWI, what disease caused 1/3 of all soldier's deaths?", "answer": "Spanish Flu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc8816de0eb824d4052fc", "question": "What is Camp David's official name?", "answer": "Naval Support Facility Thurmont -- President Eisenhower named it Camp David after his grandson, David.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa82", "question": "In which large bay would you find the Belcher Islands?", "answer": "Hudson Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a52", "question": "What musical instrument's name means \"bells playing\" in German?", "answer": "Glockenspiel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c403", "question": "What color is soapstone when it is first mined?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42c", "question": "The Himalayas are located on which continent?", "answer": "Asia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8a99901dd7bf43be5e750", "question": "In \"The Farmer in the Dell\", what did the cat take?", "answer": "The rat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d6", "question": "What is Canada's popular winter ice sport that is not hockey?", "answer": "Curling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9fb", "question": "Marbella is a resort on which SpanIsh coast?", "answer": "Costa del Sol", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339737", "question": "What is the number of the Mobile Army Surgical Hospital in \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "4077", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfc5c9dc5ec6cd98a831b", "question": "Who painted \"The Birth of Venus\"?", "answer": "Sandro Botticelli", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a354", "question": "What is the only US state that borders a Canadian territory?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8cee294b094db915830ab", "question": "Who is credited with creating McDonald\u2019s\u2019 Big Mac?", "answer": "Jim Delligatti", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c6", "question": "Which year did Charles J. Guiteau shoot US President James Garfield?", "answer": "1881", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e94527ccba3ffe45786d2", "question": "What year was the element Californium first synthesized?", "answer": "1950", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59636aea967692ea851899a1", "question": "On July 4th of what year was the Declaration of Independence adopted?", "answer": "1776", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600241a24be4723ccac2217a", "question": "Who is the queen of the fairies in Shakespeare\u2019s \"A Midsummer Night\u2019s Dream\"?", "answer": "Titania", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399b2", "question": "What athlete played co-pilot Roger Murdock in the 1980 movie \"Airplane!\"?", "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394dd", "question": "What kind of animals are \"Pinky and the Brain\"?", "answer": "Lab mice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b41d", "question": "Johann Schober was the first president of what modern-day organization in 1923?", "answer": "Interpol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133993b", "question": "What character on the original Star Trek TV series was played by James Doohan?", "answer": "Scotty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a715", "question": "The coast of what National Seashore is known as the \"Graveyard of the Atlantic\"?", "answer": "Cape Hatteras National Seashore", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c2749076251badbeace", "question": "How many U.S. Presidents fathered no children?", "answer": "Five -- George Washington, James Polk, Warren Harding, James Buchanan, and Andrew Jackson fathered no children.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f6", "question": "Who is the adopted son of Vito Corleone?", "answer": "Tom Hagen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57a", "question": "Coney Island is located on what island?", "answer": "Long Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf84", "question": "What is British politician William Hague's middle name?", "answer": "Jefferson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afda", "question": "Who was America's adversary at the Battle of Midway?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58e2f54e2e77afa695b03104", "question": "What is the capital of Maldives?", "answer": "Mal\u00e9", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b7", "question": "The Columbia River flows into what body of water?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008e5fcf842fa4c4ba96b1", "question": "Which year was the \"Battle of Jutland\" fought?", "answer": "1916", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59029f21cad1ec93f27df75c", "question": "At what popular Seattle market did Starbucks open its first store in 1971?", "answer": "Pike Place", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaea", "question": "What is the capital of Ghana?", "answer": "Accra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf19", "question": "An onomastician studies what?", "answer": "Names", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d49", "question": "What year did The Louvre open as a museum?", "answer": "1793", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe938516bd93ce3a4e5f683", "question": "Koinoniphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Rooms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a88120565ad31a57c7f6", "question": "Which American author was awarded both the Nobel Prize in Literature and Presidential Medal of Freedom?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071cd83745b36be73039d0", "question": "Who worked as the lead Soviet rocket engineer during the Space Race between the United States and the Soviet Union?", "answer": "Sergei Korolev", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133937a", "question": "What does Elwood steal from the gas station in the movie \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "Wiper blades", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b1ad4fda37788a9a1db3", "question": "Which author wrote \"The Regeneration\" trilogy?", "answer": "Pat Barker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c994", "question": "What was Marie Curie's husbands name?", "answer": "Pierre", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b45a", "question": "Who led over 900 followers in a mass suicide in 1978?", "answer": "Jim Jones", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b666", "question": "In the game of 9-ball, the pool balls are initially placed in a grouping of what shape?", "answer": "Diamond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391aa", "question": "Who played James Bond in the 1971 film \"Diamonds Are Forever\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "593c4becb8198b9a2b077967", "question": "In which of the \"Die Hard\" films does Samuel L. Jackson star in?", "answer": "Die Hard with a Vengence", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb6597e83c707845b2127", "question": "What is the term for when flocks of starlings swoop and swirl in unison?", "answer": "Murmuration", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ad", "question": "What does the legal term \"Persona non grata\" mean?", "answer": "An unwelcome person", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b0d6e662d71a53650fcd", "question": "What is the name of Argus Filch's pet cat?", "answer": "Mrs. Norris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd536e347d002c297e4b6", "question": "Which book did James Fenimore Cooper publish in 1826 that was later made into a movie, starring Daniel Day-Lewis?", "answer": "The Last of the Mohicans", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d01a2596a59cbdfbd377", "question": "Who said, \"I'm a success today because I had a friend who believed in me, and I didn't have the heart to let him down\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ff", "question": "Which US state's official song is \"On the Banks of the Wabash, Far Away\"?", "answer": "Indiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c421", "question": "What movie award appears in the International Radio Alphabet?", "answer": "Oscar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a296", "question": "Billy Joel's \"Uptown Girl\" music video featured which supermodel?", "answer": "Christie Brinkley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdd5ff70499cffc60b84237", "question": "Apart from the toga, what was the main article of Roman fashion?", "answer": "Tunic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4d9ae308b8581f80b092c0", "question": "While filming a segment for the show \"The Grand Tour\", what car did Richard Hammond crash in June, 2017?", "answer": "Rimac Concept One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b373", "question": "What country's explorers discovered the site of Pensacola, Florida?", "answer": "Spain's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc6a", "question": "How many Super Bowl appearances did Brett Favre lead as part of the Green Bay Packers?", "answer": "2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abb5", "question": "What is the capital of Malawi?", "answer": "Lilongwe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe0dc07fcbed638185eaa0b", "question": "Where was the first Disney theme park outside the U.S. built?", "answer": "Tokyo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a82", "question": "Nick Carraway was the narrating lead character in which classic novel?", "answer": "The Great Gatsby", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb7e", "question": "How many red squares are there on a standard checker board?", "answer": "32", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339847", "question": "Who released the album \"I Got Dem Ol' Kozmic Blues Again Mama\"?", "answer": "Janis Joplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be1", "question": "What year was Elvis born in?", "answer": "1935", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab13cbbaab681b0929216e", "question": "In the automotive world, what does the abbreviation CVT stand for?", "answer": "Continuously Variable Transmission", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c8dc877e98cb977789ed", "question": "Which US state is home to Olympic National Park?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf40", "question": "Who patented the safety razor in 1895?", "answer": "King Gillette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e58", "question": "In the movie \"Speed\", dropping below what speed will blow up the bus?", "answer": "50 mph", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017381644491cbd7c5a1794", "question": "During World War II, prisoners wearing an inverted pink triangle in a concentration camp signified the prisoners were what?", "answer": "Primarily homosexual men, bisexual\u00a0men,\u00a0transgender women and sexual offenders, as well as,\u00a0pedophiles\u00a0and\u00a0zoophiles.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f0", "question": "What is the fear of heredity known as?", "answer": "Patroiophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c5", "question": "What year marked the publishing of Bram Stoker's novel \"Dracula\"?", "answer": "1897", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c7d", "question": "Who is the creator of the \"Desperate Housewives\" TV series?", "answer": "Marc Cherry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c2", "question": "What is Albumen the correct term for?", "answer": "Egg White", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c50", "question": "Who directed the 1968 \"Planet of the Apes\" movie?", "answer": "Franklin J. Schaffner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c767", "question": "What blood cell deficiency gets its name from the Greek meaning \"being without blood\"?", "answer": "Anemia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe0e518fcbed638185eaa2a", "question": "Which city has been awarded the most total Michelin stars as of 2020?", "answer": "Tokyo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c439877e98cb9777899c", "question": "What country is home to \"Snake Island\"?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feba9907e83c707845b20d6", "question": "What breed of dog's evidence is first legally admissible in court?", "answer": "The Bloodhound is the first breed of dog that's evidence is legally admissible in some U.S. courts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded043ea2747c8aff16d25", "question": "What fruit is a cross between a blackberry and a red raspberry?", "answer": "Tayberry", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa2", "question": "What are wrapped in bacon to make the dish \"Angels on Horseback\"?", "answer": "Oysters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bc40d96d05b23b281655", "question": "What documents were responsible for establishing the 17th Parallel as the line that separated Vietnam during the Vietnam War?", "answer": "Geneva Accords", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b493e49076251badbeaad", "question": "In 1952, the United States Air Force created Project Blue Book to study what?", "answer": "Unidentified Flying Objects (UFOs)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac46", "question": "How many of the seven wonders of the ancient world still stand?", "answer": "One - the Great Pyramid of Giza", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6002424c4be4723ccac22183", "question": "In Chaucer\u2019s \"The Canterbury Tales\", the pilgrims are travelling to visit the shrine of which saint?", "answer": "Saint Thomas Becket", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a392", "question": "What was renamed to Ho Chi Minh City in 1975?", "answer": "Saigon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9bb7d364247bf200fb8a4", "question": "Which UK group won the 1981 Eurovision Song Contest?", "answer": "Bucks Fizz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db751e0ab2c8f322317fe4", "question": "Peridot is the birthstone for which month?", "answer": "August", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa1c", "question": "In what Australian state would you find Parkes?", "answer": "New South Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b255", "question": "What Ken Kesey-led group toured American in a psychedelic school bus called \"Further\"?", "answer": "The Merry Pranksters", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abef", "question": "What country borders Ukraine to the east?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2da", "question": "What is the monarch butterfly sometimes called?", "answer": "Milkweed butterfly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b3231cebf195a31e15d7387", "question": "Also known as the \"Chile Pine\", what is the common name of the tree \"Araucaria araucana\"?", "answer": "Monkey puzzle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe6a4a220565ad31a57c7c0", "question": "What are Rocky and Bullwinkle\u2019s full names?", "answer": "Rocket J. Squirrel and Bullwinkle J. Moose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339261", "question": "Who had the fingers on his left hand glued together to make his disability look more real in the movie \"The Usual Suspects\"?", "answer": "Kevin Spacey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ffe", "question": "What is the occupation of Mary Poppins?", "answer": "Nanny", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca47", "question": "What is the more common name for grape sugar?", "answer": "Glucose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e2", "question": "In sports, what does IIHF stand for?", "answer": "International Ice Hockey Federation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0bc", "question": "Which film director's films include \"Raging Bull\" and \"Goodfellas\"?", "answer": "Martin Scorsese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c556", "question": "In which decade was Louise Brown, the first test tube baby born?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133937f", "question": "Who played Jane Fonda's love interest in the movie \"On Golden Pond\"?", "answer": "Dabney Coleman", "category": "entertainment"}]